{
  "at001" : {
    "front" : "How are PGI wines labelled in __Austria__?",
    "back" : "*Landwein*",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "law"]
  },
  "at002" : {
    "front" : "What are the primary differences between __Austrian__ and __German__ *Prädikat* systems?",
    "back" : "1. *Kabinett* is not a *Prädikatswein* in __Austria__\n2. __Austria__ has two additional *Prädikate* levels: *Ausbruch* and *Strohwein*\n3. higher minimum must weights in the __Austrian__ *Prädikate*",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "law", "pradikat", "de"]
  },
  "at003" : {
    "front" : "What is *Strohwein*?",
    "back" : "Wines made from grapes laid out on beds of straw or reeds over the winter to concentrate sugars.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "viniculture", "law", "pradikat"]
  },
  "at004" : {
    "front" : "Where does *Ausbruch* slot in the __Austrian__ *Prädikate* system?",
    "back" : "*Ausbruch* is a classification between *Beerenauslese* (BA) and *Trockenbeereauslese* (TBA)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "law", "pradikat"]
  },
  "at005" : {
    "front" : "What is the *Districtus Austriae Controllatus* (DAC)?",
    "back" : "DAC is a category and a set of regulations, agreed upon by the producers from a specific appellation, on the variety (or varieties) and wine style that best expresses the region.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "law"]
  },
  "at006" : {
    "front" : "Name the *DACs* in __Austria__.",
    "back" : "There are 7 DACs in __Austria__:\n\n* Wachau/Kamptal DAC\n* Kremstal DAC\n* Traisental DAC\n* Weinviertel DAC\n* Leithaberg DAC\n* Mittelburgenland DAC\n* Eisenberg DAC",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "hard",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "law"]
  },
  "at007" : {
    "front" : "What are the terms used to categorize dry white wines in the __Wachau__?",
    "back" : "* *Smaragd* - fullest bodied and most complex style\n* *Federspiel* - in between\n* *Steinfeder* - lightest, freshest style",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "winestyle"]
  },
  "at008" : {
    "front" : "Where are the vineyards situated within __Austria__?",
    "back" : "Eastern end of __Austria__, away from the __Alps__ of the west and the south.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["at", "geography"]
  },
  "at009" : {
    "front" : "Describe the growing climate in __Austria__.",
    "back" : "__Austrian__ vineyards have a *moderate continental* climate with *high diurnal range* and long ripening seasons.\n\nNorthern regions experience cooling northerly winds, while southeastern regions close to __Hungarian__ border are warmed by easterly winds.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "climate"]
  },
  "at010" : {
    "front" : "How much area is under vine in __Austria__?",
    "back" : "Approx. 45,000 hectares.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tags" : ["at", "viticulture"]
  },
  "at011" : {
    "front" : "What is the principal grape variety grown in __Austria__? What is its percentage of production?",
    "back" : "*Grüner Veltliner*\n\nApprox. 30% of all plantings in __Austria__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["at", "varietals", "viticulture", "gruner_veltliner"]
  },
  "at012" : {
    "front" : "What is the typical flavour profile of a quality *Grüner Veltliner*?",
    "back" : "*Grüner Veltliner* has a broad range of flavours:\n\n* *green apples*, *salad*, and *white pepper* when young\n* layers of *honey* and *toast* with age\n* marked *minerality* with low yields on appropriate soils",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "varietals", "winestyle", "gruner_veltliner"]
  },
  "at013" : {
    "front" : "Which areas produce the best *Rieslings* in __Austria__?",
    "back" : "__Wachau__, __Kamptal__, and __Kremstal__ produces outstanding *Rieslings*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "varietals", "riesling"]
  },
  "at014" : {
    "front" : "Describe a quality __Austrian__ *Riesling*.",
    "back" : "Quality __Austrian__ *Rieslings* are usually *dry*, *full-bodied*, with ripe, peachy primary fruit, and commonly have mineral flavours.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "winestyle", "varietals", "riesling"]
  },
  "at015" : {
    "front" : "Name 4 commonly grown white varieties in __Austria__",
    "back" : "Commonly grown white varieties in __Austria__:\n\n* *Grüner Veltliner*\n* *Welschriesling*\n* *Riesling*\n* *Chardonnay*\n* *Neuburger*\n* *Müller-Thurgau\n* *Sauvignon Blanc*",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "varietals"]
  },
  "at016" : {
    "front" : "What is the most commonly planted black variety in __Austria__?",
    "back" : "*Zweigelt* - a *Blaufränkisch* x *St Laurent* cross",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "varietals", "zweigelt"]
  },
  "at017" : {
    "front" : "What style of wine does *Zweigelt* produce?",
    "back" : "Very deep coloured reds with soft tannins and bramble fruit.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "winestyle", "varietals", "zweigelt"]
  },
  "at018" : {
    "front" : "Describe a quality *Blaufränkisch*.",
    "back" : "Quality *Blaufränkisch* wines have moderate tannins, crisp acidity, peppery, sour cherry, and strong mineral flavours.\n\nWines aged in oak produces wines with softer acidity and a sweeter fruit profile.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "winestyle", "varietals", "blaufrankisch"]
  },
  "at019" : {
    "front" : "What is the name of the __Austrian__ specialty variety that produces wines of similar profile to *Pinot Noir*?",
    "back" : "*St Laurent*",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tags" : ["at", "winestyle", "varietals", "st_laurent", "pinot_noir"]
  },
  "at020" : {
    "front" : "True or False\n\nQuality __Austrian__ wines are typically consumed by the export market.",
    "back" : "False\n\nFine wines of __Austria__ are consumed by the large wealthy local markets well before they have a chance to reach the export markets.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["at"]
  },
  "at021" : {
    "front" : "List the four generic PDOs in __Austria__.",
    "back" : "1. __Niederösterreich__ (Lower Austria)\n2. __Burgenland__\n3. __Steiermark__ (Styria)\n4. __Wien__ (Vienna)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "geography", "law"]
  },
  "at022" : {
    "front" : "How many subregions are there in __Niederösterreich__?",
    "back" : "8",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "geography", "law"]
  },
  "at023" : {
    "front" : "Which is the first __Austrian__ DAC?",
    "back" : "*Weinviertel DAC*\n\nWines labelled as *Weinviertel DAC* are among the best in __Austria__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "law"]
  },
  "at024" : {
    "front" : "Name the subregions of __Burgenland__.",
    "back" : "1. __Neusiedlersee__\n2. __Neusiedlersee-Hügelland__\n3. __Mittelburgenland__\n4. __Südburgenland__",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "geography", "law"]
  },
  "at025" : {
    "front" : "Why are prices for sweet wines from __Neusiedlersee__ and __Neusiedlersee-Hügelland__ regions generally lower than similar wines from __France__ or __Germany__?",
    "back" : "Autumn mists from the __Neusiedlersee__ lake and its surrounding wetland regions encourage noble rot almost every year.\n\nAlso, vineyards are on the plains and yields are relatively high for sweet wines.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "viticulture", "climate", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "at026" : {
    "front" : "What grape variety are the best __Austrian__ red wines made from?",
    "back" : "*Blaufränkisch* or blends of *Blaufränkisch* and __Bordeaux__ varieties.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["at", "varietals", "blaufrankisch"]
  },
  "at027" : {
    "front" : "True or False\n\nRed wine blends are covered by the *Austrian DAC* regulations.",
    "back" : "False",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tags" : ["at", "law"]
  }
}
